<?xml version="1.0"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lcl">
    <!--
  ====================================================================
    LConv
  ====================================================================
-->
    <module name="LConvEnconding">
      <short>Contains routines and tables to convert text between various encodings.</short>
      <descr/>
      <!-- unresolved type reference Visibility: default -->
      <element name="SysUtils">
        <short/>
        <descr/>
        <seealso/>
      </element>
      <!-- unresolved type reference Visibility: default -->
      <element name="classes">
        <short/>
        <descr/>
        <seealso/>
      </element>
      <!-- function Visibility: default -->
      <element name="CPConvert">
        <short/>
        <descr/>
        <errors/>
        <seealso/>
      </element>
      <!-- function result Visibility: default -->
      <element name="CPConvert.Result">
        <short/>
      </element>
      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="CPConvert.s">
        <short/>
      </element>
      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="CPConvert.from">
        <short/>
      </element>
      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="CPConvert.toC">
        <short/>
      </element>
      <!-- function Visibility: default -->
      <element name="GetDefaultCodepage">
        <short/>
        <descr/>
        <errors/>
        <seealso/>
      </element>
      <!-- function result Visibility: default -->
      <element name="GetDefaultCodepage.Result">
        <short/>
      </element>
      <element name="GuessEncoding">
        <short>Guess character encoding of a string.</short>
        <descr>The returned encoding can be used with other functions of this unit. GuessEncoding uses some heuristics to find out a good encoding. For example it checks for magic numbers like utf BOM. Next it checks if it could be UTF-8. Finally it returns the system encoding.
This function can be used to find the encoding of text files.</descr>
      </element>
      <element name="ConvertEncoding">
        <short>Converts the character encoding of a string</short>
        <descr>ConvertEncoding uses has tables to convert between almost any desired encoding. The parameters for this function are:
s - The string to be convert
FromEncoding - The encoding of the string s
ToEncoding - The encoding of the result
The encodings are specified as string values, and the following values are currently supported:
'utf8' - UTF-8, the standard Unicode encoding of the LCL
'ansi' - Ansi represents whatever is the current system locale in a single-byte or multi-byte encoding, but never in a word encoding like UTF-16
'utf8bom' - Indicates that the text is in UTF-8 and starts with a UTF-8 byte order mark
'ucs2le' - UCS 2 encoded in little endian byte order
'ucs2be' - UCS 2 encoded in bif endian byte order
'iso88591' - ISO 8859-1 Latin 1
'iso88592' - ISO 8859-2 Latin 2
'cp1250' - CP1250
'cp1251' - CP1251
'cp1252' -
'cp1253' -
'cp1254' -
'cp1255' -
'cp1256' -
'cp1257' -
'cp1258' -
'cp437' -
'cp850' -
'cp852' -
'cp866' -
'cp874' -
'cp936' -
'cp950' -
'cp949' -
'cp932' -
'koi8' - KOI8
</descr>
      </element>
      <element name="GetDefaultTextEncoding">
        <short>Returns the common text encoding of the current operating system.</short>
        <descr>At the moment it gives:
Under Windows it returns the windows codepage.
Under Darwin (Mac OS X) it returns UTF-8.
Under all other Unix (e.g. Linux, BSD, Solaris) it uses the environment variables LC_LANG, LC_MESSAGE, and LANG. This is nowadays typically UTF-8.</descr>
      </element>
      <element name="NormalizeEncoding">
        <short>Trims, shorten and lower case the given encoding</short>
      </element>
      <element name="GetSupportedEncodings">
        <short>Fills the list with all basic encodings</short>
        <descr>It does not add all encodings that are supported by the operating system. For example iconv under Linux supports hundreds of encodings.</descr>
      </element>
    </module>
    <!-- LConv -->
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
